# Khanh Nguyen

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Professional in Software Engineering with 5 years experience in various kinds of Project such as Windows Applications , Web Applications and recently move up to the Cloud Based-Applications. 4 out of 5 years experience with the Japanese companies and Japanese culture. Hard-work, dedicated and artisans in Software Engineering, Bilingual (Japanese and English) as well as native in Vienamese (a well-known Outsourcing Development Country). I am looking for opportunities in the Cloud Based-Web Application as well as Full Stack Development. 5 years working in multicultural environment and loving to be part of an international teams and join my hand in innovative projects where creativity and productivity are the core values. I'm available for hire now, drop me a messages if you are interested in.

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

Languages: PHP, .NET, SAP ABAP, Java, Flash Action Script 3.0, C++

Technologies: Cloud Computing (AWS), Virtualization

Framework/Tools: Laravel, Cake PHP, Symfony, Entity Framework, LAMP Stack, Eclipse

Jenkins, Ansible, Puppet

OS: Windows Server, Centos 6.5, Ubuntu

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Cloudpack, Tokyo, Japan

2016/04 - Present

Bridge Software Engineer / Web Application Engineer (full-time)

- Web Development with PHP, Laravel Frameworks, based on Cloud Infrastructure, focusing on Availability, Accessibility, Scalability, Durability web applications
- Deploy Web Applications to Cloud and develop autonomated CI tasks.
- Use my communications skill to act as a "bridge" between Japanese colleagues and Offshore Development center in Vietnam.

### Accomplishments

- Become a DevOps of one of the biggest Golf Reservations System in Japan
- Get certificated by AWS as an Associate Solutions Architect and several internal cloud-related certifications
- Always keep up with the latest technologies both in Cloud Computing and Web
   Applications and applied them to current project such as Vue.js, Progressive Web Apps...
   to deliver the most excellent Application to customers.

# FPT Information Systems, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2013/10 - 2016/3

Bridge Software Engineer (full-time)

- Maintain and Operate chemistry Sales and Delivery Systems (written in VB.NET). Act as a Bridge between Japanese IT Help Desk and Thailand IT Helpdesk to resolve tickets from users
- Participate in Development new SAP Systems with SAP ABAP especially in Sales and Delivering Module.
- Besides, also consult to end user about how to improve system's reliability and durability such as move to the clouds and how to backup data efficiently
- Estimation project costs and deadline for new features

## Accomplishment

- Understands the workflow below big company in Chemistry, understand how departments interact and exchange data between them.
- Experience with one of the biggest ERP application (SAP)

# Luxoft Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2012/10 - 2013/10

Junior Action Script Developer (full-time)

- Develop the HEAD-UNIT (Main Control Menu) for Mercedes cars in Flash (Action Script 3.)
- Perform Unit Test to enhance the quality as well as detect potential bugs inside the system Accomplishment
  - As a junior developer in team , I learned a lot from others elite engineers from task scheduling to coding quality.
  - Working in a multinational professional engineers was a chance to enhance my English skills, and experience with multicultural environment

#### **INTERN / PART-TIME EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

2011/10 - 2012/10

Projects of different scales involving Full Stack Development, as well as maintenance and migration old framework. Focusing mainly on .NET Technology and its ecosystems

Accomplishments (see below, and more)

Windows application to input Contract in Insurance Company.( VB.NET)

- Windows Application in Medical for Scanning and Detecting disease in Breast (Migration from VB6 to VB.NET)
- Renew mobile website of Airlines company (Java Struts 1)

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Freelance.com 2012/09 - Present

Flash Freelance developer

Working on various projects, such as E-Commerce and Company introduction websites. Working as a freelancer, bring me the chance to work freely, and increasing my skill on estimation project cost and deadline.

Accomplishments

Zoes.co.es: a full-flash company profile website that needs a lot of complex tweenings and animation, all of them were delivered by code not by GUI helps the company IT Department to change easier and more effective. Languages: Flash, Action Script 3.0

wewearit4u.com :a websites that promotes your business by wearing T-Shirt , riding bicycles with your company logos around the city . Languages : PHP, Flash, Action Script

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

**AWS Associate Developer Certification** Nov 2017 - Nov 2019

**TOEIC L&R: 890** Sep 2017

**AWS Associate Architect Certification** Jun 2017 - Jun 2019

Japanese Language Profiency Test: N2 Jul 2016

Pearson Summit 2 Certification May 2013

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering

FPT University, Vietnam

Sep 2009 - May 2013

### **LANGUAGES**

Japanese: High Intermediate

Fluent English: